(イタチ)今夜は 満月だよ サスケ。
There's a full moon out tonight, Sasuke.
(サスケ)あう～。
フフッ。
(イタチ)何だ!?
What…?
(マダラ)さあ 出てこい 九尾！
Come on out…
Nine Tails!
Itachi's Story - Light and Darkness:
The Genius
(イタチ)何だ？ この感じ。
What is this sensation?
うぅ…。
(イタチ)よしよし。
There, there…
泣くな サスケ。
Don't cry, Sasuke.
何があっても お兄ちゃんが
絶対 守ってあげるからな。
No matter what happens, your big brother
will definitely protect you…
Summoning Jutsu!
口寄せの術！
ま まさか…。
No way!
やれ 九尾。
Go, Nine Tails!
よし よしよし。
It's okay. There, there!
It's the Nine Tails!
九尾だ！
化け狐が出たぞ！
The Demon Fox is on the loose!
なんだってんだよ。
とにかく逃げるのよ バカ！
What's going on?!
Just run, you idiot!
Sasuke!
サスケ…。
よしよし。
びっくりしちゃったな。
It's okay.
You got a little scared, huh?
警務部隊より発令。
This is an announcement
from the Leaf Police!
非戦闘員は
辰巳の避難所へ向かえ。
All civilians are to evacuate
to the southeast shelter!
辰巳の避難所だ！
The southeast shelter!
Dad! Mom!
(イズミ)お父さん！ お母さん！
Come here!
(イタチ)こっちに来い！
(イズミ)イタチ… 君？
Itachi!
早く！
う うん！
Hurry!
Okay!
避難所へ行くよ。
We're going to the shelter.
うん。
こっちだ 急げ！
This way! Hurry!
Mom!
先に行って。
イタチ君？
Keep going.
Itachi?
みんないるから。
Everyone will be there.
落ち着いて！
ここは大丈夫だ！
Please stay calm!
You're safe here!
父さん。
Father!
(フガク)お前なら
無事でいると思っていた。
I knew you would be all right.
Get to the shelter quickly.
避難所へ急げ。
うん。
Okay.
(ヒルゼン)里の外へは追いやった。
We drove it out of the village.
手をゆるめず
次々に仕掛けるのじゃ！
Don't let up. Keep attacking!
避難は おおかた終了しました。
Just about everyone has
been evacuated.
隊長！ 我々も九尾を。
Captain, we'll go after
the Nine Tails as well.
警務部隊は 非戦闘員を保護する。
The Leaf Police Force is to remain
and protect the civilians.
しかし 隊長！
But Captain!
These are the Village's orders.
それが里からの命令だ。
What was that just now?!
なんだ？ 今のは。
Looks like they sealed the Nine Tails…
九尾を封印したようだ。
なんとかな…。
…somehow.
(ヒルゼン)四代目火影 ミナトと
その妻 クシナをはじめ→
Many lives were lost
including the Fourth Hokage Minato
and his wife, Kushina…
多くの生が失われた。
事件の全容は いまだわからぬ。
The facts behind the incident
are still unknown…
《イタチ : 命は生まれる》
Life is born…
(ヒルゼン)だが しかし 今はただ→
But for now, let us
mourn our comrades…
我々の仲間の死を
悼もうではないか。
《命は死ぬ…》
And life…dies.
(イズミ)イタチ君！
Itachi!
あ あの… あのときはありがとう。
Thank you for before…
イタチ君のおかげで助かった。
Because of you, I was safe!
死なないでよかったね。
I'm glad you didn't die.
うん… アハッ。
(イズミ)妹？
(イタチ)弟だ。
Your younger sister?
Younger brother.
(イズミ)抱っこしていい？
(イタチ)ダメだ。
Can I hold him?
No.
どうして？
泣くと困る。
Why not?
I don't want him to cry.
泣きまちぇんよね～？
You're not gonna cry, are you?
よ～しよし。
There, there!
よしよし。
むぅ… 何よ！
Aww, come on!
(ダンゾウ)九尾の襲撃により
里のあちこちが被害を受けた。
The Nine Tails' attack caused
devastation throughout the village.
その復興にあたり 里の区割りを
いくつか変更しようと思う。
For the reconstruction,
we've decided to revise a number
of the village's boundaries.
油女一族は こちらの地区へ
移ってもらいたい。
We'd like the Aburame Clan
to move into this district.
かねてより
一族で 森を所有したいとの→
The clan previously submitted
a request to occupy the forest,
申し出があったので
それを考慮した。
so we took that into consideration.
奈良一族は
被害地区ではないので そのまま。
The Nara Clan's territory was
not part of the stricken area,
so they will remain where they are.
被害を受けた警務部隊本部は
ここに建て直す。
The Leaf Police Force headquarters
which sustained damage,
will be rebuilt here.
それにともない うちは一族も…。
(フガク)ダンゾウ様！
And the Uchiha Clan will move along
with the headquarters…
Lord Danzo!
うちはは
里の治安を守る警務部隊。
The Uchiha Clan makes up
the Leaf Police Force
that protects the Hidden Leaf.
その場所では 里の中央部から
離れすぎています。
As such, that location is too far
from the village center.
緊急の任務には対応できません！
We wouldn't be able to act swiftly
in an emergency.
緊急のときには 暗部が出る。
We have the ANBU Black Ops
for such emergencies.
クッ…。
警務部隊は訓練のための→
The Leaf Police has to commute
to the training grounds, does it not?
演習場通いを
しているのであろう。
ここならば 訓練をするのに
適した土地のそばだ。
This location is near an area
that's ideal for training.
うちは専用の
演習場として使うがよい。
You can use that area exclusively
for the Uchiha's training grounds.
続けるぞ。
Continuing on…
警務部隊本部の
移転にともない→
In conjunction with the reconstruction
of the Leaf Police Headquarters,
the Uchiha Clan will also relocate.
うちは一族にも
移転してもらう。
崩壊を免れた家屋は…。
Home and buildings that
were spared will be…
九尾事件のとき→
During the Nine Tails Incident,
俺たち
うちはを使わなかったのは→
we Uchiha were not called upon
because they feared that
うちはが写輪眼で九尾を
操ることを危惧したんでしょう。
we would use our Sharingan to
manipulate the Nine Tails.
それどころか
九尾事件を引き起こしたのが→
Even worse, there are some who say
うちはの者じゃないかと
言うヤツらまでいる！
that the Uchiha
caused the Nine Tails Incident!
俺たちを里の隅っこへ追いやって
動きを制限する気だ！
They are sending us to the outskirts of
the village in order to keep an eye on us!
そもそも二代目の時代に→
This is just like during
the Second Hokage's era
俺たち一族は
里の一角に集められて→
when the Uchiha were rounded up
and isolated in one part of the village!
隔離されたような
ものじゃないか！
今度は 更に遠くへ！
This time, it's even farther away!
The village suspects us!
里は 俺たちを疑っているんです。
Captain, we can't accept this decision!
隊長 こんな移転
納得がいきません！
断固拒否するべきです！
We should reject it outright!
隊長！
Captain!
お前たちの意見は もっともだ。
You are absolutely right.
だが 移転は
他の一族も受け入れている。
But the other clans have accepted
their respective relocations as well.
うちはだけが
拒むわけにもいかない。
The Uchiha cannot be
the lone voice of dissent.
しかし 隊長！
But Captain!
条件面では交渉する。
I'll do what I can to negotiate
the conditions.
だが 移転は
受け入れなければなるまい。
But we must accept the move.
他の者たちにも伝えてくれ。
以上だ。
Pass the word around. That is all.
解散！
Dismissed.
(フガク)お前は どう思う？
How do you feel?
見に行こうよ 父さん。
ん？
Let's go and see it, Father.
新しい演習場。
The new training grounds.
(イタチ)俺は好きだな ここ。
そうか。
I like it here.
Is that so?
父さん 術を教えてよ。
Father, teach me jutsu…
うちは代々の。
よし！
Generational Uchiha Jutsu…
through the generations.
All right!
これが うちはの基本忍術
火遁 豪火球の術だ。
This is a fundamental Uchiha Ninjutsu…
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu.
いいか？ 印は順に…。
All right, the signs are…
できた。
I did it!
フッ フハハハハハ！ 驚いたな。
What a surprise.
さすが 俺の子だ。
That's my boy.
(イタチ)もうすぐ引っ越しだね。
We'll be moving in no time, huh?
(フガク)ああ。
Yeah.
どうしたの？
What's the matter?
うむ…。
《囲まれてる… というのが
気のせいならいいが…》
We're surrounded…
I wish it was my imagination, but…
なに？
What is it?
いや もうすぐというなら
お前だぞ イタチ。
It's nothing…
"In no time," huh? The same could
be said about you, Itachi.
６歳になるからな。
Since you're going to be
six years old soon.
CONGRATULATIONS ON
ENTERING THE ACADEMY
Congratulations on your acceptance
into the Academy, everyone!
皆さん 入学おめでとう。
From this day forth,
これからは
忍の道を目指す者として→
do your best to reach your goals
to become a shinobi.
大いに励んでください。
I'm sure some of you have already
been taught ninjutsu in your households…
(大黒)あぁ キミたちのなかには→
すでに 家で 忍術を
学んでいる者もいると思うが→
But here at the Academy,
you will also train
アカデミーでは 仲間との連携や→
to coordinate and work together as
a team when you are in a group.
隊を組んだときの
集団行動も訓練する。
The fundamentals are very important,
make sure you learn them well.
(大黒)基本は重要だ。
しっかりと学ぶように。
(カマノ)フン。
(大黒)さて カマノ 答えは？
All right, Kamano. What's the answer?
I don't know!
わっかりませ～ん！
(大黒)では イタチ。
Then…Itachi?
印は水遁 水弾の術です。
The seal is for the Water Style:
Water Bomb Jutsu.
Correct.
(大黒)よろしい。 みんな
覚えとけ ここテストに出すぞ。
Keep that in mind everyone.
It will be on the test.
Itachi…Come at me.
イタチ 来いよ。
ん？
よし はじめ！
All right!
Begin!
ダーッ うわっ！
(大黒)そ… それまで。
The match is over!
Okay, okay…
はいはい。
ごめんよ。 また今度ね サスケ。
Sorry, Sasuke.
Some other time, okay?
う～。
おかえり 父さん。
術を教えてよ。
Welcome home, Father!
Please teach me jutsu!
術？ アカデミーで
教えてくれるだろう。
Jutsu?
Aren't they teaching you
at the Academy?
It's too easy.
やさしすぎる。
お前には そうだろうな。
I guess it would be for you.
(フガク)演習場で待ってろ。
うん。
Wait for me at the training grounds.
Okay!
(ミコト)晩ご飯までには
帰ってきてね。
Make sure you're home by dinner.
Got it!
わかった。
Look over there! It's Itachi!
ほら あそこ イタチ君よ。
どこどこ？
Where?
Oh, he's walking. He's so cool!
歩いてる かっこいい！
あっ こっち見た！
Oh, he's looking this way!
(カマノ)あぁ いかんな。
そうは思わんかね 諸君。
This is not good.
Don't you think, gentlemen?
か… 彼のためにもね
このまま調子にのって→
For his sake,
if he gets swept up by all of this
and gets the wrong idea…
なんか勘違いでも
されようものなら…。
I agree.
まったくですな。
(カマノ)生意気なんだよ！
He's stuck up!
It's me! He's looking at me!
私よ 私を見てるのよ！
私よ！
No, it's me!
あっ また歩いた イタチ君が歩いた！
He started walking again!
Itachi's walking!
He's walking!
しめるぞ。
(２人)おう！
It's decided then…
- Yeah!
- Right!
うわっ イッテー！
Ouch!
急に飛び出して
くんじゃねえよ バカ！
Don't jump out at us like that, idiot!
(ドカン)バカ？
誰に向かって バカ言うか？
"Idiot"? Who are you calling "idiot"?
(ドカン)お前ら １年だな？
You guys must be freshmen!
人に…。
ひっ！
You…
ぶつかっておいて…。
うわっ！
…run into someone…
バカって…。
and call 'em an "idiot"…?
ぶつかってきたのは
そっちじゃねえか！
You ran into us!
なんだ～!?
What did you say?!
(カマノたち)うわ～っ！
待て～！
Hold it!
Who the hell are you?
何だ お前は!?
ソイツらの仲間か!?
A friend of theirs?
ん？
今年の１年は…。
All the freshmen this year are…
生意気ばっかりか！
…stuck up!
ぐわっ！
(カマノたち)すっげぇ！
- Wow!
この人を保健室へ。
う… うん。
Take him to the infirmary.
O-Okay.
ホントに強いんだね イタチ君。
君？
Itachi, you're really strong, my friend!
"My friend"?
Even upperclassmen are
easy targets for you, sir!
上級生も瞬殺ですね イタチさん。
さん？
"Sir"?
どけどけ イタチ様のお通りだ！
Move it, move it!
Master Itachi is coming through!
様？
"Master"?
道をあけろ！ イタチ様だ！
Make way!
It's Master Itachi!
(イタチ)やめてくれ 頼む。
- Move it! Make way!
- Stop it…
- Outta the way!
- Please…
やめてくれ。
Don't…
《イタチ : 命は生まれる。
There is birth…
命は死ぬ》
and death…
《命は 群れる。
Life…
flocks together…
SHINOBI
忍って何だ？
What is a shinobi?
里って 何だ？》
What is a village?
上期の成績 全科目１位か。
First in every class,
according to your progress report…
さすが俺の子だ。
That's my boy.
父さん。
ん？
Father…
Hmm?
術を教えて。
Teach me jutsu.
もっと知りたいんだ 忍のこと。
I want to know more
about being a shinobi.
In cases like this, always make sure
you have an escape route.
This is important.
If you're in a four-man team…
(シスイ)その年で いい腕だな。
You're very talented for your age.
(イタチ)シスイさんには かなわない。
I'm no match for you, Shisui.
よく言う。
Oh come on…
どうした？
アカデミーは退屈で さぼったか？
What's wrong?
Does the Academy bore you
so much that you're ditching?
さぼってなんかいないよ。
I'm not ditching.
テメエら きたねえぞ！
You guys! That's unfair!
ハハハッ！
何だ その目は！
What's with that look?
コラーッ！ やめんか お前ら！
Hey! Cut it out!
全員 止まれ！
Hey you, stop!
イタチ！
Itachi!
Take this!
食らえ！
なんだ？
消えた…。
What happened?
He disappeared?!
ああ… 消えた。 消えたよ！
Yeah, he disappeared!
He disappeared!
(大黒)これは 分身… いや…。
That's a clone…
No…
影分身の術？
It's a Shadow Clone Jutsu!
どうした？
戻らないと。
What's the matter?
I have to get back.
そうか。
You do?
シスイさん。
うん？
Shisui…
(イタチ)どうして命は争うんですか？
Why is there fighting in life?
Who knows?
さあな。 でも…。
But…
止められる争いなら
俺は やめさせたい。
If the fighting can be stopped,
I'd like to stop it.
俺も。
Me too!
またな。
See you later.
Aside from the clone jutsu
(大黒)うちはイタチは
昨年の卒業課題である→
which is a requirement for
graduating the Academy,
分身の術どころか→
禁術にあたる
影分身の術まで マスターしています。
Itachi Uchiha has already mastered
the Shadow Clone Jutsu, a forbidden jutsu.
他のすべてにおいても優秀で→
He excels in all other subjects.
There's no purpose in keeping him
at the Academy any longer.
これ以上 アカデミーにおいておく
意味はないでしょう。
だが まだ１年ではないのか？
はい。
Isn't he just a freshman?
Yes.
よいではないか 前例はある。
That doesn't matter.
This has happened before.
あれらとは時代が違う。
今は戦時ではない。
That was a different era.
This is not the age of war.
そやつ 天才なのだろう。
The boy is a genius, no?
あんな生徒は
見たことがありません。
I've never seen a student like him.
卒業させたほうが イタチのためか。
So it will be better for Itachi
to let him graduate?
(フガク)卒業？
Graduate?
１年で… アカデミーをか？
(イタチ)うん。
After only a year at the Academy?
Yeah.
両親が許可すればって
先生が言ってた。
The teacher said as long as
both parents agree.
父さんに学校に来てほしいって。
They want to talk to you at school.
そうか。 さすが 俺の子だ。
I see…
That's my boy.
あう… あ…。
ああ… 卒業生諸君。
GRADUATES' INFORMATION SESSION
GRAD
これから キミたちには→
里からの任務が
与えられるわけだが→
今後は スリーマンセルの班を作り→
各班ごとに
１人ずつ 上忍の先生がつき→
その先生の指導のもと
任務をこなしていくことになる。
では これから班分けを発表する。